git was a tool designed for version control so you could easily work on a project and add new versions with branches, basicaly just making the whole process much easier. github is a website like a hub of projects that adds ui to the tool making collaboration easy. Github is also nice for accessing other peoples codes so you can use them like libraries.
git branches help you seperate parts of a project so you can work on new features without changing the original code
pull requests let everyone in the project review the changed code safetly, encourages a collaborative enviroment with no changes being made without everyone knowing
